CAMERON KINGSLEY

Full Stack Software Developer

Contact

Cameron.Kingsley13@gmail.com (425) 236-1912 Seattle, WA <u>LinkedIn</u> <u>Github</u> Motivated full stack software developer with experience building full stack applications using React, JavaScript and Ruby on Rails. Eager to contribute to great teams and provide creative solutions. Ready to utilize 7+ years in construction management, bringing excellent problem solving, team building, project & time management skills. I also enjoy getting my hands dirty in the workshop building furniture, props, guitars, tabletop miniatures, or anything else that provides a challenge and opportunity to try new skills.

Portfolio

www.cameronjameskingsley.com

Skills

Frontend:

ReactJS, Redux JavaScript, Node.js Bootstrap HTML/CSS

Backend:

Ruby, Rails, Sinatra PostgreSQL, SQLite3 ActiveRecord Heroku

Miscellaneous:

Git, SmartGit (studying) Python Unity, C# Arduino, C 3D Modeling & CAD Photoshop/Illustrator

Education

Flatiron School

March 2021 - Dec 2021

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails & JavaScript program.

University of Washington

2009 - 2014

Bachelor of Arts Architectural Design

Bachelor of Science Construction Management

Technical Projects

Fallout CellMate - <u>Github</u> - <u>Demo</u> - React, Redux, Rails API, Heroku Project Management App for Fallout Cascadia game development

- Deployed and currently in use by the Fallout Cascadia Dev Team
- ReactJS/Redux frontend & Rails API backend with PostgreSQL database
- Incorporated Discord OAuth2 server side user authentication & creation

CyberBug <u>Github</u> - <u>Demo</u> - React, Redux, JavaScript, Rails API, PostgreSQL Full Stack Application to create, manage, and resolve software bugs

- Utilized JSON Web Tokens with localStorage to store encrypted user data
- Created RESTful Rails API, ReactJS frontend with async fetch requests
- Implemented Redux for state management and API fetch requests
- Focus on best practices to create clean, DRY, & modular components.

Who Are You? - <u>Github</u> - <u>Demo</u> - JavaScript, Rails API, PostgreSQL, Heroku Questionnaire app to generate a character backstory for RPG games

- JavaScript frontend with RESTful Rails API backend
- Implemented asynchronous functions for API requests and animation.

Experience

Fallout Cascadia Dev. Team: Level Designer June 2

June 2021 – Current

- Working with a multidisciplinary team to create a massive Fallout 4 mod.
- Responsible for level design using base and custom team created assets to generate a new Pacific Northwest based game world.

Ferris-Turney: Sr. Project Engineer

August 2020 – Jun 2021

- Led multiple construction projects to completion on time and on budget
- Prepared budgets & schedules, evaluated vendor quotes & subcontracts
- Coordinated cost and time efficient constructibility solutions with team
- Overhauled submittal process and automated much of the data entry

Swinerton Builders: Sr. Project Engineer

July 2016 - May 2020

• Estimating, procurement, scheduling & coordination with team members

Stellar J Corporation: Project Engineer

June 2014 - July 2016

Managed 3D & BIM modeling, created drawings and details